# Luis Echenique

anchastreluis@gmail.com | +58 412 831 2251 | /in/echeniqueluis/ | gitlab.com/sentustudios | artstation.com/anchastreluis

### Resumen

```
var myStack = [
"HTML", "CSS", "Node.js", "express.js", "Firebase", "React.js",
"React Native", "Docker", "GraphQL", "AWS", "MongoDB", "d3.js",
"Python", "Dart", "Flutter", "Swift", "kotlin"
];
```

"Programming is simple. But producing good code is an art, and achieving it is a lifelong journey."

I'm a 3d artist and a software architect.

As an artist I find myself able to create 3D models with photo-realistic textures optimized for commercial rendering and use in game engines like Unreal Engine and Unity 3D, projecting the quality of Latest Generation Games and application of internal programming algorithms for their interactivity for the entertainment industry and industrial product simulation.

As a programmer, who developed apps for iOS and Android phones natively through the Flutter framework, I bring solutions like Freelance to contribute to the vision of UI/UX design specialists, transforming your work into code optimized to maintain your vision, aesthetics and animations, along with the knowledge of API-Rest development in both Python with Flask and Django, and Javascript with Nodejs and Firebase, to achieve effective communication by creating web, mobile, desktop environments with server infrastructures.

## Work Experience

### Android and iPhone developer. January 2018 - Actual.

In charge of the development of mobile apps for iOS and Android. Transform UI/UX designs into functional applications. Connect to API-Rest and apply asynchronous communication techniques. App deployments in respective app stores. Offering troubleshooting solutions with **120%** effectiveness by improving the client - server software architecture. { myStack }

### SabioGuruStudio. 2D and 3D designers. June 2012 - May 2018 (6 years).

I developed applications under the Restful Api concept for web, mobile and desktop environments. Transform the vision and ideas of the client into virtual realities and high-performance augmented reality as 3D Artist Visualizers, increasing the customer capture impact by **80%**.{ myStack + [blender, Unity 3d, Unreal Engine]}

# Fundación Centro Nacional de Desarrollo e Investigación en Tecnologías Libres - CENDITEL. Free Technologies Development Analyst. March 2017 - November 2017 (9 months).

I implemented the use of the frontEnd and backEnd structure to organize the effective and functional development of applications as a Free Technology Development Analyst increasing development effectiveness by 20% with an impact on the final product of **150%** in stability. { myStack + [django] }

Unidad de Control de Gestión de la Gobernación Del Estado Mérida. Software Developer - Professional Fees. September 2016 - August 2017 (1 year).

I developed custom applications using Functional Javascript methodologies by applying game theory-based artificial intelligence algorithms by increasing flow control and data volume analysis by \*\*190%\*. { myStack }

3D.CR. Senior 3D Visualizer. July 2016 - December 2016 (6 months).

3D Artist Visualizers with workflow of Interpreting prototypes in 2d planes and recreating simulations for the optimization of 3D parts improving the consto-benefit ratio by **45%**. { Gimp, inkscape, blender, python, html, css, javascript }

CORPIVENSA. Senior 3D Visualizer. June 2012 - November 2012 (6 months).

3D artist of industrial parts, where I approached optimization solutions with the use of free software and applying agile processes process an increase of production of 3d objects by **60%** of high quality to apply simulation. { blender, python, freecad }

Cuerpo de Ingenieros de la Aviación. DevOps - Systems Architect - Civilian Staff. October 2009 - June 2012 (2 years 9 months).

I planned and implemented policies and procedures to ensure that administrative operations are automated to achieve **300%** efficiency in the institution's bureaucratic dynamics. { myStack + [DevOps, software architecture, Linux Server] }

Ministerio del Poder Popular para la Defensa. Assistant of Architecture - Designer. July 2008 - June 2012 (4 years).

3D Artist Visualizers Interpret Architectural, Civil Engineering, Electrical and Mechanical Plans in the 3d world, maintaining and optimizing on local servers in the best and most advanced way, information in reconstruction and creation of 2D planes to the technological vanguard bringing the increase of efficiency by **800**% when moving from paper art and nibs to digital formats. { myStack + [Autodesk, DevOps] }

INCE - MILITAR. Computer Assisted Design Instructor. October 2010 - November 2011 (1 year 2 months).

Designed to convey the ability and competence needed to perform element calculation, determine the most appropriate materials, make machining process decisions and their subsequent deployment in both 2d and 3d, that is, to carry out a mechanical, civil or architectural project with professional quality with both commercial tools

and free software, to increase the effectiveness of the work by more than \*\*120%\*. { Autocad, LibreCAD, OpenCASCADE, python }

### UMT de Venezuela. DevOps | Technician in Systems. June 2006 - October 2008 (2 years 5 months).

Manage and manage the assembly of the distributed computing platform, including its peripherals, to ensure levels of availability, performance and security appropriate to customer requirements. { software architecture }

#### INTERDAV. network supervisors. January 2003 - June 2006 (3 years 6 months).

Logistic Network Administrator, Programmer. Backup Platform Management.

```
{ Linux Server Local, c }
```

### TERVICA. Administrative Assistant Training. January 2002 - July 2002 (7 months).

To execute the administrative processes of the Business area, applying the defined rules and procedures, preparing the necessary document, reviewing and performing calculations, in order to comply with each of these processes, achieve timely results and ensure effective service delivery. { xhtml, c, basic }

### Education

- Universidad de los Andes (VE). Bachelor's Degree, Ciencias físicas · (2015 2020)
- Universidad Nacional Abierta, Caracas. Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering (2005 2010)
- Centro de Diseño Digital. Professional Designer, Diseño y artes aplicadas · (2002 2005)
- Instituto Diocesano Pablo VI. Técnico Medio en Administración Financiera, Comercio y Servicios Administrativos · (1996 - 2002)